Pachter, Henry M.; Papers ger071
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Articles Published in Journals, 1929-1987; Undated; 5
  - "Leisure – the Wealth of man: Henri Rabasseire replies:" Clipping, 1958 Spring (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 30)
  - "The Pattern of Sociological Theory." Clipping, 1958 Fall (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 31)
  - "Foreign Policy: a Revolutionary Alternative: Henry Pachter replies:" Clipping, 1959 Winter (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 32)
  - "The Pope … and the Papers." Clipping, 1959 January (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 33)
  - "Politics and Economics in Southeast Asia." Clipping, 1959 Fall (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 34)
  - "Changes in the Communist World: A Critical Comment." Clipping, 1959 Spring (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 35)
  - Vigilanten und Dinosaurier." Clipping, 1959 April (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 36)
  - "Die Verheissung bleibt ihnen lebendig." Clipping, 1959 October (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 37)
  - "Co-Existence Revisited." Clipping, 1959 October (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 38)
  - "Paradoxes of Foreign Aid." Clipping, 1960 June (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 39)
  - "The Meaning of 'Peaceful Coexistence'." Clipping, 1961 January-February (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 40)
  - "A Foreign Policy." Clipping, 1961 Winter (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 41)
  - "Yankee no." Clipping, 1961 February (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 42)
  - "Koexistenz als Idee und Strategie." Clipping, 1961 March (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 43)
  - "Rätselhafte Revolution." Clipping, 1961 April (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 44)
  - "Forschungs-Manager und Staats-Manager." Clipping, 1961 May (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 45)
  - "In Washington nichts Neues." Clipping, 1961 June (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 46)
  - "Germany Looks in the Mirror of History." Clipping, 1961 July (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 47)
  - "Kennedy nach Kuba und Wien." Clipping, 1961 July (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 48)
  - "The G.S." Clipping, 1961 Fall (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 49)
  - "The So-called Berlin Question." Clipping, 1961 Fall (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 50)
  - "George Kennan: The Perils of History." Clipping, 1961 Fall (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 51)
  - "Die Negerfrage ist keine ökonomische Frage." Clipping, 1961 October (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 52)
  - "Amerikas 'neuer' Neger." Clipping, 1961 December (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 53)
  - "Radikalismus in den USA." Clipping, 1962 February (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 54)
  - "The Legend of the 20th of July 1944." Clipping, 1962 Spring (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 55)
  - "Vereinte Nationen – Uneinige Regierungen." Clipping, 1962 March-1962 April (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 56)
  - "Radikalismus in den USA." Clipping, 1962 April (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 57)
  - "Wie Kennedy regiert." Clipping, 1962 August (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 58)
  - Abolishing the Octopus." Clipping. Fall, 1962 Fall (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 59)
  - "Polarisierung der Weltpolitik." Clipping, 1962 December (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 60)
  - "Amerikas Republikaner." Clipping, 1963 (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 61)
  - "Collective Guilt Disputed." Clipping, ca. 1963 (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 62)
  - "Der Ost-West-Konflikt." Issue, 1963 (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 63)
  - "Amateur Diplomats and the Peace Literature." Clipping, 1963 Spring (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 64)
  - "The U.N.'s 17th Assembly." Clipping, 1963 Winter (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 65)
  - "Amateur Diplomats and the Peace Literature." Clipping, 1963 Spring (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 66)
  - "Popes and Communists." Clipping, 1963 June (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 67)
  - "Taking Issue With 'Armegeddon'." Clipping, 1963 Summer (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 68)
  - "Cuba Discussion." Clipping, 1963 Summer (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 69)
  - "Automatisierung in Amerika." Clipping, 1963 July-1963 August (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 70)
  - "Rassenstreit als Verfassungskampf." Clipping, 1963 July-1963 August (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 71)
  - "Amerika, ein Produkt des 18. Jahrhunderts." Clipping, 1963 September (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 72)
  - "Kapitalistische und Wohlfahrtsplanung in Amerika." Clipping, 1964 (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 73)
  - "The Best of all Social Democracies?" Clipping, 1964 Winter (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 74)
  - "Verhandeln ohne Illusionen." Clipping, 1964 February (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 75)
  - "Capitalism, the Welfare State, and Socialism." Issue, clipping, 1964 Spring (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 76)
  - "Weisheit oder Ratlosigkeit?" Clipping, 1964 April (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 77)
  - "Johnsons Dilemma." Clipping, 1964 July-1964 August (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 78)
  - "Die ersten beiden Jahre Johnsons." Issue, 1964/1965 (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 79)
  - "Das Ost-West-Verhältnis und die amerikanischen Interventionen in der Dominikanischen Republik und Vietnam." Issue., 1964/1965 (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 80)
  - "Von Roosevelt bis Kennedy." Clipping, 1965 February (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 81)
  - "Vietnam and the Left." Typescript, clipping, 1965 Fall (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 82)
  - "JFK as an Equestrian Statue: On Myth and Mythmakers." Clipping, 1966 (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 83)
  - "Die Kluft weitet sich. Schwarze und Weiße in den USA." Clipping, 1966 January-February (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 84)
  - "Johnsons zwei Kriege." Clipping, 1966 February (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 85)
  - "'Neuer' Linksradikalismus in den USA." Clipping, 1966 April (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 86)
  - "Uses and Abuses of Civil Disobedience." Clipping, 1966 May-1966 June (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 87)
  - "Die UNO und die deutsche Frage."Clipping, 1966 September-October (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 88)
  - "Marxism and America's New Left." Clipping, 1967 January (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 89)
  - "Let's Talk Sense About Oswald." Clipping, 1967 March-April (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 90)
  - "Lessons of Middle East Crisis."Clipping, 1967 June 18 (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 91)
  - "Troubles of a Jewish Conscience." Clipping, 1967 July (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 92)
  - "Chinas Vertretung in den Vereinten Nationen." Clipping, 1976 August (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 93)
  - "Das Deutschlandbild der Amerikaner." Clipping, 1967 September-October (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 94)
  - "Zur Einführung" [Weltmacht Rußland]. Clipping, 1968 (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 95)
  - "Notes on the Soviet Union." Photocopy, 1968 (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 96)
  - "The Movement Is the Message." Clipping, 1968 January-February (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 97)
  - "The Intellectual as Diplomat." Clipping, 1968 March-1968 April (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 98)
  - "Jewish Righteousness and Left-Wing Antisemitism." Clipping, 1968 Spring-Summer (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 99)
  - "Revisionist Historians and the Cold War." Clipping, 1968 November-1968 December (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 100)
  - "Glossen: Nixon vor der amerikanischen Krise." Clipping, 1969 January-1969 February (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 101)
  - "The Nixon Regime And Foreign Policy." Clipping, 1969 January-1969 February (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 102)
  - Classified Military Research and the University: In Response." Clipping, 1969 January-1969 February (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 103)
  - "Teaching Negro History." Clipping, 1969 March-1969 April (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 104)
  - "Reflections on Unilateral Intervention." Clipping, 1969 May (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 105)
  - "Der Westen blickt nach Rußland." Clipping, 1969 June (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 106)
  - "On Being an Exile. An Old-Timer's Personal and Political Memoir." Clipping, 1969 Fall-1970 Winter (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 107)
  - "The Strike at the Free University." Clipping, 1970 January (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 108)
  - "On Re-Reading Hermann Hesse." Clipping, 1970 Spring (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 109)
  - "Engages Science – or Scientists?" Clipping, 1970 July-1970 August (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 110)
  - "The Problem of Imperialism." Clipping, 1970 September-1970 October (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 111)
  - "Nazi with a Human Face?" Clipping, 1970 November-1970 December (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 112)
  - "Views on Israel." Clipping, 1971 February (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 113)
  - "Willy Brandt Under Fire." Clipping, 1971 June (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 114)
  - "A Philosophy for the New Left." Clipping, 1971 Fall (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 115)
  - "The New Shape of Foreign Policy." Clipping, 1971 October (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 116)
  - "Die Legende von WeiMarch" Clipping, 1971 November-1971 December (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 117)
  - "The Intellectuals and the State of WeiMarch" Clipping, 1972 Summer (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 118)
  - "Die Ohnmacht der Polizei." Clipping, 1973 May-1973 June (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 119)
  - "Paul Goodman – A 'Topian' Educator." Clipping, 1973 Fall (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 120)
  - "Gutenberg ist noch nicht tot." Clipping, 1973 September-1973 October (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 121)
  - "When the Government is Lying…" Clipping, 1974 (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 122)
  - "Détente – Reality and Myth." Clipping, 1974 Winter (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 123)
  - "The Idea of Progress in Marxism." Clipping, 1974 Spring (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 124)
  - "Imperialism in Reverse." Clipping, 1974 June (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 125)
  - "The Shah of Iran, Is He a Marxist?" Clipping, 1974 Summer (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 126)
  - "Defining an Event: Prolegomenon to Any Future Philosophy of History." Clipping, 1974 Fall (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 127)
  - "Orthodox Heretic, Romantic Stalinist [George Lukács]." Clipping, 1975 Spring (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 128)
  - "The issue redefined: the Cold War – what was it?" Clipping, 1975 May-1975 June (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 129)
  - "The Private Lives of Rebels." Clipping, 1975 (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 130)
  - "Who are the Palestinians?" Clipping, 1975 Fall (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 131)
  - "Heidegger and Hitler. The Incompatability [!] of Geist and Politics." Clipping, 1976 (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 132)
  - "Nostalgia and Revision: The Vogue of Weimar Culture." Clipping, 1976 Summer (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 133)
  - "The Revolt of the French 'New Philosophers'." Typescript, 1977 (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 134)
  - "Was Weimar Necessary?" Clipping, 1977 Winter (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 135)
  - "Requiem For A National Socialist [from Weimar Études]." Clipping, 1977 Summer-Fall (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 136)
  - "Foreword" [to The Letters of Rosa Luxemburg]. Clipping, 1978 (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 137)
  - "What Do We Ask of Eurocommunism?" Clipping, 1978 Winter (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 138)
  - "Gershom Scholem – the Myth of the Mythmaker." Typescript, 1978 Winter (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 139)
  - "Freedom, Authority, Participation." Clipping, 1978 Summer (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 140)
  - "Aggression as Cultural Rebellion: The German Example." Clipping, 1978 Summer (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 141)
  - "Ghosts of the Cold War." Clipping, 1978 Fall (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 142)
  - "Letters: The Politics of Anti-Realism." Clipping, 1979 Winter (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 143)
  - "Masters of Cultural History II: Friedrich Meinecke and the Tragedy of German Liberalism." Clipping, 1979 Winter (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 144)
  - "Paris (post World War II) Looks at Berlin (pre World War I)." Clipping, 1979 April (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 145)
  - "Thoughts About Stokie." Clipping, 1979 Spring (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 146)
  - "Unfair to Marx." Clipping, 1979 Summer (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 147)
  - "Marx and the Jews." Clipping, 1979 Fall (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 148)
  - "Masters of Cultural History III: Johan Huizinga – The Historian as Magister Ludi." Clipping, 1979 Fall (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 149)
  - "Walther Rathenau. Musil's Arnheim or Mann's Naphta? Clipping, 1980 (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 150)
  - "Introduction" [Social Research]. Clipping, 1980 Spring (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 151)
  - "Yekkes and Ostjuden: Conflicting Words in the Germany of My Youth." Clipping, 1980 May 25 (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 152)
  - "Brecht's Personal Politics." Clipping, 1980 Summer (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 153)
  - "Lewis Mumford – American Savonarola?" Clipping, 1980 Summer (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 154)
  - "On Germans and Jews." Clipping, 1980 Fall (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 155)
  - "After Afghanistan – Round Three." Clipping, 1980 Fall (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 156)
  - "In Response to George Steiner." Clipping, 1980 Fall-1981 Winter (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 157)
  - "Response: History In America." Clipping, 1980 Fall-1981 Winter (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 158)
  - "Again: Marx and the Jews." Clipping, 1981 Spring (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 159)
  - "The Ambiguous Legacy of Eduard Bernstein." Clipping, 1981 Spring (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 160)
  - "The Radical Émigré in the Metropolis." Clipping, 1982 (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 161)
  - "Theorien und Ideologen." Clipping, 1982 (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 162)
  - "Images of the New Life." Typescript, 1983 (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 163)
  - "Ghosts of the Cold War." Clipping, 1987 Fall (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 164)
  - "The Economics of Fascist Rule." Typescript, Undated (Box 3 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 165)
  - "The Idea of Progress in Marxism." Reprint, Undated (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 1)
  - "Der Kampf der Generationen." Reprint, Undated (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 2)
  - "Kommunismus und Klasse." Photocopy, Undated (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 3)
  - "Stages of Totalitarian Economy." Reprint, Undated (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 4)
  - Margaret Scotford Archer / Salvador Giner:Contemporary Europe. Review. Offprint, 1972 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 5)
  - Paul A. Baran / Paul M. Sweezy:Monopoly Capital: An Essay on the American Economic and Social Order. Review. Clipping, 1967 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 6)
  - Karl Dietrich Bracher:The German Dictatorship. Review. Clipping, 1971 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 7)
  - Joseph Buttinger:Am Beispiel Österreichs. Review. Clipping, 1954 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 8)
  - Joan Campbell:The German Werkbund. Review. Clipping, 1978 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 9)
  - Stephen F. Cohen:Bukharin and the Bolshevik Revolution. Review. Photocopy, 1974 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 10)
  - Charles Delzell:Mussolini's Enemies. Review. Clipping, 1963 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 11)
  - Edward E. Ericson:Radicals in the University. Review. Clipping, 1970 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 12)
  - Louis Fischer:Russia's Road from Peace to War. Review. Clipping, 1977 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 13)
  - Philipp Frank:Das Kausalgesetz und sein Grenzen. Review. Clipping, 1933 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 14)
  - Erich Fromm:The Sane Society. Review. Clipping, 1956 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 15)
  - Peter Gay:Freud, Jews and Other Germans; John Murray Cuddihy: The Ordeal of Civility. Review. Clipping, 1978 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 16)
  - Antonio Gramsci:Gramsci – Stalinist Without Dogma. Review. Clipping, 1974 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 17)
  - Alexander Heard:The Costs of Democracy. Review. Clipping, 1960 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 18)
  - Richard Hiscocks:Democracy in Western Germany; Leonard Krieger: The German Idea of Freedom. Review. Clipping, 1959 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 19)
  - Peter Hoffmann:The History of the German Resistance 1933-1945. Review. Clipping, 1977 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 20)
  - Chang Tu Hu:China: Its People, Its Society, Its Culture. Review. Clipping, 1960 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 21)
  - Rodney W. Jones:Urban Politics in India. Review. Clipping, 1975 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 22)
  - Douglas Keller: "Korsch's Revolutionary Historicism." Review. Clipping, 1976 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 23)
  - George F. Kennan:Memoirs 1929-1950. Review. Clipping, 1968 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 24)
  - Donald Peterson Kent:The Refugee Intellectual. Review. Clipping, 1953 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 25)
  - Kurt Kluxen:Vorlesungen zur Geschichtstheorie. Review. Clipping, 1975 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 26)
  - Milton Kovner:The Challenge of Coexistence. Review. Clipping, 1961 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 27)
  - Walter Laqueur:Weimar – A Cultural History. Review. Clipping, 1976 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 28)
  - J. Lenz:Die 2. Internationale und ihre Erbe. Review. Clipping, 1932 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 29)
  - Kurt London:Unity and Contradiction. Review. Clipping, 1962 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 30)
  - Emil Lousse:Grundbegriffe der Geschichte. Review. Clipping, 1967 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 31)
  - Frank E. and Fritzie P. Manuel:Utopian Thought in the Western World. Review. Clipping, 1980 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 32)
  - William McCord:The Spring Time of Freedom. Review. Clipping, 1965 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 33)
  - Florence Miale / Michael Selzer:The Nuremberg Mind. Review. Clipping, 1980 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 34)
  - L. Mosse / M. George:The Crisis of German Ideology. Review. Clipping, 1967 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 35)
  - W. W. Rostow:The Stages of Economic Growth. Review. Clipping, 1960 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 36)
  - Trent Schroyer:The Critique of Domination. Review. Clipping, 1973 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 37)
  - Franz Seitz / Anatole Dauman:The Tin Drum. Film review. Clipping, 1980 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 38)
  - Albert Speer:Inside the Third Reich. Review. Clipping, 1971 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 39)
  - Hans Speier / W. Philips Davison:West German Leadership and Foreign Policy. Review. Clipping, 1959 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 40)
  - Alfred Stern:Philosophy of History and the Problem of Values. Review. Clipping, 1965 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 41)
  - Fritz Stern:Gold and Iron. Review. Clipping, 1978 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 42)
  - Hans-Jürgen Syberberg:Hitler, ein Film aus Deutschland. Film review. Clipping, 1980 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 43)
  - Hugh Thomas:Cuba: The Pursuit of Freedom; K. S. Karól: Guerrillas in Power. Review. Clipping, 1972 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 44)
  - Antonio Vásquez de Espinosa:Compendio y Descripción de las Indias Occidentales. Review. Clipping, 1949 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 45)
  - John Willett:Art and Politics in the Weimar Period 1917-1933. Review. Clipping, 1979 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 46)
  - William Appleton Williams:The Roots of the Modern American Empire. Review. Clipping, 1970 (Box 4 (5-Articles Published in Journals), Folder 47)
- Published Newspaper Articles, 1932-1986; Undated; 6
  Arranged alphabetically.
  This series, the largest series in the collection, has been kept in its original order, as received from Pachter's estate. His contributions to German and American newspapers are arranged in folders by topic. In many cases, only a copy of the published article is present in the folder, however typescripts of some articles are also included in the folders. This series, which contains over 7,000 items, demonstrates not only the prolific nature of Pachter's journalistic career, but also the vast range of topics he addressed in his writings.
  - Alphabetical folder listing. Typescript, Undated (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 48)
  - Adenauer., 1948-1967 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 49)
  - Administration, 1949-1972 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 50)
  - Africa, 1952-1970 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 51)
  - Alaska, Puerto Rico, Hawaii, 1954-1967 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 52)
  - The American Mind, 1950-1971 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 53)
  - American in Europe, Europeans in America, 1950-1970 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 54)
  - Antarctic, Arctic, 1955-1958 (Box 4 (6-Published Newspaper Articles), Folder 55)